Ajay has suffered
[music]
Welcome to the Consumer Commission
friends, today we will discuss about a Supreme Court
judgment. In this matter,
I did not even ask for the player's
car to be replaced, but the court
ordered the replacement of the car. Do
n't forget that the court has given a lot of punishment in many other matters also.
This
matter was of Andheri Motors India Limited and
Shailendra Kumar, the judgment of which was given
in the year 2009. This matter was decided because the
car had met with a very serious accident, it was such a
terrible accident, it hit a pole, it
started dragging from the side and the
car got completely mixed up. The
passengers sitting in the car got badly injured,
despite that the airways did not open, which was due to the
special features of that car, that if there is ever an
accident or any such unfortunate incident, the
airways will protect them. This has been
considered a manufacturing defect in the court. The matter
started with the State Commission. The State Commission,
after looking at all the facts, gave its order
that it should be set at a low level.  The vehicle should be replaced
and the accused should be brought to the composition commission for an order.
After that, the matter came to the National Commission. The
National Commission also
examined all the facts very closely and
confirmed the order of the State Commission. When the matter
came to the Supreme Court, the Supreme Court
re-examined all the documents that were
presented before the State Commission and the National Commission. The
complaint stated that there was such a serious accident
that the vehicle was totally damaged,
despite this the airlines did not open it, whereas I had
spent so much money to buy such an expensive
car so that the vehicle of ES passengers could be
confirmed. And when the exam is
not opened, then
what benefit did they get from spending so much? The first thing
was the arrogance of the complaint that the air bags
opening itself shows that the
vehicle was defective. Secondly, the complaint was
that when the advertisement is given for selling the vehicle, it is
displayed and its
features are highlighted, then it was
not mentioned anywhere when the air bags
will open and when they will not open, let alone whether they will open or not. But
when he complained to those several motorists,
they had said that  The
impact was not so pure that the air bags would
open, air bags fly when there is a very strong
shock, so this thing was
never shown anywhere by the dealer or the manufacturer, nor was it written or told
to the consumers, only
and only like our features that
we have air bags, this whole back
in itself shows this thing which
shows that the back will open whenever there is a
problem of constipation and the passengers will open and the third
reason Trump said that if there was
not so much force, there was not so much shock, then
see how the car got so
damaged and how the passengers got so
injured, so much fun can happen only
when there is a lot of ejaculation and there is a lot of shock, so
saying these three things the
company has said that the difference in the company's tax is that
now it takes
half and there is an impact on them, so
looking at these three things the State Commission did
its investigation and the National Commission investigated,
now the matter reached the Supreme Court, then the
Supreme Court also heard it carefully
and looked at its behavior, acquisition of the company  The
company's arm hole was done as
told earlier for Impact and Fortuner that the
force should be so much that it gets
affected and the back opens automatically.
Secondly, any Aspire Kwid also produces a
complaint about what happened, how it happened,
where the air bag opened, how much
impact it had, how strong the injury was,
all these things should have been attended to by expert opinion
and presented before the court. The
third thing said was that when the vehicle was
taken, there was no mention of replacement in the complaint, then the order should not have been placed by the
commission. The
replacement order placed in the commission has been done without
prior permission, which is not correct. The next
point which was said was that the
dealer was not made a party, hence there
is no preventive contract between the complainant and the manufacturer, that there is no
direct contract between the consumer and the manufacturer
unless the dealer intervenes. The
dealer was not made a party
and the vehicle was purchased from the dealer.
And the last thing it was also said was that it should be done
by time limitation because time limitations
It starts when the vehicle is purchased and a
lot of time has passed since the purchase, this time
limitation should start from the time the
complaint is made and the problem has been imposed from the moment the accident happened,
so the Supreme Court
heard all these arguments and gave its order
that the order for replacement can be given by the Supreme
Court, can any court
because of course all the things are
examined minutely and it sees whether relief should be
given to the consumer, there is
no Food Commission bond that the replacement
of the vehicle should be considered only that much,
Jasvir, it cannot be a more disgusting repair,
so the Supreme Court, State Commission,
National Commission, everyone has the power to
see what needs to be done, hence replacement is
not wrong in any way, for this the
Supreme Court has given many previous orders in its own
judgment in which they have given
release to the Panch Maha without any reason,
relief should be given in any way, secondly regarding the
force, the Supreme Court
believes that the force was so much that the vehicle got
total damaged and the airways still did not
open, firstly, secondly this argument
in itself is wrong  It is said that there should be so much force
that the hair work opens, if it is at the risk of someone's life and property
then the ear backs will open, then is this
not Shetty,
why would any consumer stand and spend money for this, first of all,
theft is wrong, secondly, even if it is complete, it is
also correct that the
impact was very strong, the car was completely
damaged and there is no need for any kind of evidence,
in this, evidence or
expert opinion is required
when things are not visible in front of you, so there is
a thief
that Hrithik's liquid, there is no need for
any kind of ABS for the thing which is visible in front,
so in this matter also there was
no need to start anything else here and secondly, this matter of force is neither
written anywhere in the terms and conditions, nor
in any display, any alarm which is
highlighted, it is displayed in its features, it is
not written anywhere that how much force will be there
and what will be the appropriate force and when will the ear back be taken,
in itself policy theft is
wrong and that is why the Supreme Court also
accepted that this is not only a deficiency but also  It is a
deficiency, rather it is an answer, it is an internal
part of the company to manufacture the thing in this manner,
hence the
Supreme Court has termed it as a manufacturing defect case and
hence the replacement of the watch was also
not prohibited by a primitive contract. The
Supreme Court did not deny the primitive contract for what purpose it was to
show that the vehicle was not manufactured, so that
after that it
authorizes the dealer to sell it. This does
not mean that if the dealer is not involved then
basically the problem was in
manufacturing, the vehicle was
not manufactured at all. By default, there is no
question of a preventive contract in this. Whether the
dealer is from Delhi or not, it would
only mean that the
item was purchased from a particular dealer for which the invoice shows
that this dealer sold and bought and there was no
laxity on his part. Basically, the car was
not manufactured by his company,
hence he should answer for everything and be
responsible for everything and
settle for less for everything.  The
responsibility to do this is of the manufacturer only. The
Supreme Court did not accept the matter of time retention
because when someone comes to know
that something is defective, it is from that day itself, otherwise the
complainant comes to know that it is
not back and it is not working and it
cannot be suffixed to the vehicle, only when it is
tested, it comes to know that
it is time limited on that day itself
and only then he comes to know that
it is
suffixed. So friends, this is a very important
landmark judgment in which it has been made
very clear that the matter of one thing is
not that it is illegal or not,
and along with that, the Supreme Court made a
very strong attack on both the time and the Supreme
Court said that the mere existence of this defect is
enough, then this
appointment is safe. Now
when will the defect arise, on which things will it arise, how much will it be, there is
no criteria for this,
while making it he said that it is
their
and their profit,
therefore, considering both the things, the Supreme
Court ordered to declare it a clear-cut manufacturing
defect and to decree it and
fixed a commission on the seventh pay from the company.
All of that was confirmed till the replacement of Jhaal litigation,
thank you very much
friends became Remo, everyone will meet again,
agree with similar new issues,
Jhaal Jhaal Jhaal Jhaal had happened.